{
    "question": "333)\uf020 _________ appointed as the new CEO of the Unique\nIdentification Authority of India (UIDAI)",
    "answer": " Pankaj\nKumar.\n"
}{
    "question": "334)\uf020 Where are the headquarters of the Unique\nIdentification Authority of India",
    "answer": " New Delhi\n"
}{
    "question": "335)\uf020 __________ topped the latest Quacquarelli Symonds\n(QS) India University Rankings 2020",
    "answer": " IIT Bombay\n"
}{
    "question": "336)\uf020 Which day is observed around the world to mark\nthe anniversary of the establishment of the UN\nCharter on this day in 1945",
    "answer": " The United Nations\nDay\n"
}{
    "question": "337)\uf020 The United Nations World Food Program\nlaunched the 'Feed Our Future' campaign in \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 87\nassociation with which Indian organization",
    "answer": " UFO\nMovies of Mumbai\n"
}{
    "question": "338)\uf020 What is the objective of the \u2018Feed Our Future'\ncampaign",
    "answer": " To create awareness and take steps\nagainst hunger and malnutrition in India.\n"
}{
    "question": "339)\uf020 Name the government authority that approves\nrevision of MSP of foodgrains",
    "answer": " The Cabinet\nCommittee on Economic Affairs (CCEA)\n"
}{
    "question": "340)\uf020 The CCEA recently approved hike in MSP of Rabi\ncrops for for which marketing season",
    "answer": " 2020-21\n"
}{
    "question": "341)\uf020 Which global financial organization recently\nreleased the \u201cEase of Doing Business\u201d for 2019-\n20",
    "answer": " The World Bank\n"
}{
    "question": "342)\uf020 India's ranking improved by how many steps in\n2019-20 Ease of Doing Business rankings",
    "answer": " 14\n"
}{
    "question": "343)\uf020 What was India\u2019s ranking in 2019-20 Ease of\nDoing Business rankings",
    "answer": " 63rd\n"
}{
    "question": "344)\uf020 Which country topped the 2019-20 Ease of Doing\nBusiness rankings",
    "answer": " New Zealand\n"
}{
    "question": "345)\uf020 Which state launched 'MukhyaMantriKanya\nSumangala Yojana' to provide a fund worth Rs\n15000 to every family where a girl child is\nborn",
    "answer": " Uttar Pradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "347)\uf020 Sakharov Prize is awarded by the European\nParliament for honouring outstanding\ncontribution in which field",
    "answer": " Fight for restoration\nof human rights\n"
}{
    "question": "348)\uf020 Who is the winner of the 2019 Sakharov\nPrize",
    "answer": " Uighur intellectual Ilham Tohti from\nChina for his attempts to \u201cfoster dialogue\u201d\nbetween Chinese people and the Uighur.\n"
}{
    "question": "349)\uf020 ________ became the 1st Indian to win a gold medal\nat the 15th Wushu World Championships in\nShanghai",
    "answer": " Praveen Kumar\n"
}{
    "question": "350)\uf020 Which bird was recently found to be the world\u2019s\nloudest bird whose shrieks can hit 125.4\ndecibels",
    "answer": " Male white bellbird of Brazil\n"
}{
    "question": "351)\uf020 Name the Bollywood actress and badminton star\nwho were named the ambassadors for Bharat Ki\nLaxmi, an initiative by Prime Minister\nModi",
    "answer": " Deepika Padukon& PV Sindhu\n"
}{
    "question": "352)\uf020 Girish Chandra Murmu has been appointed as the\n_____ of Jammu-Kashmir",
    "answer": " Lt. Governor\n"
}{
    "question": "353)\uf020 R K Mathur has been appointed as the Lt.\nGovernor of which union territory",
    "answer": " Ladakh\n"
}{
    "question": "354)\uf020 Who has been appointed as the new Governor of\nMizoram",
    "answer": " P.S. Sreedharan Pillai\n"
}{
    "question": "355)\uf020 Satya Pal Malik, till recently Governor of J&K, has\nbeen shifted to which other state as\nGovernor",
    "answer": " Goa\n"
}{
    "question": "356)\uf020 In Uttar Pradesh, Grand Diwali celebrations at\nwhich place set a world record as over 5 lakh 51\nthousand earthen lamps (Diyas) were lit\naltogether on Oct 27",
    "answer": " Ayodhya\n"
}{
    "question": "357)\uf020 Vijay Hazare Trophy is associated with which\nsports",
    "answer": " Cricket\n"
}{
    "question": "358)\uf020 Vijay Hazare Trophy is played in which format of\ncricket",
    "answer": " One day\n"
}{
    "question": "359)\uf020 Which team won the 2019 edition of the Vijay\nHazare Trophy",
    "answer": " Karnataka\n"
}{
    "question": "360)\uf020 The United Nations Day is observed on which\ndate",
    "answer": " October 24\n"
}{
    "question": "361)\uf020 Which state has decided to make government jobs\nout of bounds for people with more than 2\nchildren",
    "answer": " Assam\n"
}{
    "question": "363)\uf020 Who is the author of the book titled \"Reset",
    "answer": "\nRegaining India\u2019s Economic Legacy\"?\nSubramanian Swamy, BJP MP\n"
}{
    "question": "364)\uf020 Who has been appointed as the President of the\nBoard of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI)",
    "answer": "\nSourav Ganguly\n"
}{
    "question": "365)\uf020 Government has decided to open the entire area\nfrom Siachen base camp to Kumar Post for\ntourists. It lies in which Himalayan range",
    "answer": "\nKarakoram\n"
}{
    "question": "366)\uf020 Which company announced the launch of \u2018SBI\nCard Pay\u2019, a facility that allows contactless\npayment using mobile phones at PoS (Point of\nSale) terminals",
    "answer": " SBI Card\n"
}{
    "question": "367)\uf020 The SBI Card Pay will use NFC technology to\nprocess the contactless transaction. What is NFC",
    "answer": "\nNear Field Communication\n"
}{
    "question": "368)\uf020 18th NAM summit was held in Baku. What is\nNAM",
    "answer": " Non Aligned Movement\n"
}{
    "question": "369)\uf020 Baku is the capital of which country",
    "answer": " Azerbaijan\n"
}{
    "question": "370)\uf020 World Statistics Day is observed on October 20 at\nthe interval of how many years",
    "answer": " 5 Years\n"
}{
    "question": "371)\uf020 Ronaldo Singh bagged a gold medal in the men\u2019s\njunior Keirin event at which event",
    "answer": " Asian Track\nCycling Championships\n"
}{
    "question": "372)\uf020 The India-Myanmar Naval Exercise named ______\nwas held off the coast of Visakhapatnam, Andhra\nPradesh",
    "answer": " IMNEX-2019\n"
}{
    "question": "373)\uf020 Country's highest bridge constructed at an\naltitude of 14,650 feet is across which river",
    "answer": "\nShyok River\n"
}{
    "question": "374)\uf020 This bridge is located in which part of India",
    "answer": "\nEasternLadakh\nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 88\n"
}{
    "question": "375)\uf020 What is name of this bridge",
    "answer": " Col.\nChewangRinchenSetu\n"
}{
    "question": "376)\uf020 What is the theme for this year's International\nFilm Festival of India-IFFI",
    "answer": " Thejoy of cinema\n"
}{
    "question": "377)\uf020 The 'Crime in India 2017' annual crime report\nwas released by which apex national\norganization",
    "answer": " National Crime RecordsBureau\n"
}{
    "question": "378)\uf020 As per the Crime in India 2017 report, which state\nrecorded the maximum number of cases of crime\nagainst women",
    "answer": " Uttar Pradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "379)\uf020 Which state registered the highest number of\nrape cases at 5562( as per 2017 report)",
    "answer": " Madhya\nPradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "380)\uf020 Which Ministry launched new version of BHIM2.0\npayment app",
    "answer": " Ministry of Information\nTechnology\n"
}{
    "question": "381)\uf020 BHIM has been developed by which organization",
    "answer": "\nNPCI-National Payment Corporation of India\n"
}{
    "question": "382)\uf020 Rohit Sharma, India\u2019s famous \u2018hitman\u2019 scored his\nmaiden Test double hundred (212) playing\nagainst South Africa in which city",
    "answer": " Ranchi,\nJharkhand\n"
}{
    "question": "383)\uf020 Rohit\u2019s Test average in India rose to 99.84\nsurpassing the 71-year-old record or 98.22,\npreviously held by which person",
    "answer": " Sir Don\nBradman\n"
}{
    "question": "384)\uf020 Which international airline created a record for\nthe longest direct non-stop flight flying for 19 hrs\n16 minutes",
    "answer": " Qantas\n"
}{
    "question": "385)\uf020 Qantas is the national airline of which country",
    "answer": "\nAustralia\n"
}{
    "question": "386)\uf020 The longest non-stop flight was conducted\nbetween which two cities",
    "answer": " NewYork to Sydney\n"
}{
    "question": "387)\uf020 Sultan of Johor Cup is associated with which\nsport",
    "answer": " Hockey\n"
}{
    "question": "388)\uf020 Which country hosts the Sultan of Johor Cup",
    "answer": "\nMalaysia\n"
}{
    "question": "389)\uf020 __________ defeated India to lift the Sultan of Johor\nCup",
    "answer": " Britain\n"
}{
    "question": "390)\uf020 Joko Widodo was sworn in as President of ____",
    "answer": "\nIndonesia\n"
}{
    "question": "391)\uf020 Who has been appointed as the new President of\nthe European Central Bank",
    "answer": " Christine Lagarde\n"
}{
    "question": "392)\uf020 Where are the headquarters of the European\nCentral Bank",
    "answer": " Frankfurt, Germany\n"
}{
    "question": "393)\uf020 Name the Indian cricketer who became the first\none to play in over 100 T-20 internationals",
    "answer": "\nHarmanpreet Kaur\n"
}{
    "question": "394)\uf020 RaunakSadhwani, 13 year old boy from Nagpur\nwas in news recently for which achievement",
    "answer": "\nHebecame India\u2019s 65th GrandMaster in Chess\n"
}{
    "question": "395)\uf020 Who has been appointed as the new chairman of\nIndian Banks\u2019 Association",
    "answer": " Rajnish Kumar,\nChairman, SBI\n"
}{
    "question": "396)\uf020 Two US astronauts, Christina Koch and Jessica\nMeir, hogged international news headlines for\n____",
    "answer": "Becomingthe first all-woman pair to carry\nout a spacewalk\n"
}{
    "question": "397)\uf020 15 year old Tanishbir Sandhu won the gold in\nwhich sports in an Asian Championship",
    "answer": " Boxing\n"
}{
    "question": "398)\uf020 International Space Station is a joint project of\nspace agencies of how many nations",
    "answer": " Five\n"
}{
    "question": "399)\uf020 Anup Kumar Singh, senior IPS officer of Gujarat\ncadre has been appointed as Director-General of\nwhich elite commando force",
    "answer": " NSG-National\nSecurity Guard\n"
}{
    "question": "400)\uf020 The NCERT has decided to review the 14-year-old\nNCF for the 5th time in accordance with new\nnational education policy. What is NCF",
    "answer": " National\nCurriculum Framework\n"
}{
    "question": "401)\uf020 With which country's Air Self Defence Force,\nIndian Air Force conducted the 'ShinyuuMaitri\nexercise'",
    "answer": " Japan\n"
}{
    "question": "402)\uf020 The ShinyuuMaitri exercise was conducted at\nwhich place",
    "answer": " Panagarh, West Bengal\n"
}{
    "question": "403)\uf020 With which country India conducted a joint\nmilitary exercise named \u2018Dharma Guardian\u2019",
    "answer": "\nJapan\n"
}{
    "question": "404)\uf020 Which Indian corporate recently became the first\nIndian company to cross the total market\ncapitalisation of Rs 9 lakh crore",
    "answer": " Reliance\nIndustry Industries Ltd.\n"
}{
    "question": "405)\uf020 Which Union Ministry recently conducted the\n20th Livestock Census - 2019",
    "answer": " Ministry of\nAgriculture and Farmers Welfare\n"
}{
    "question": "406)\uf020 What is the rank of India in terms of number of\nlife stock population",
    "answer": " 1st\n"
}{
    "question": "407)\uf020 Which category of animals forms largest part of\nlivestock",
    "answer": " Cattle\n"
}{
    "question": "408)\uf020 What is the new name of the National Highway\nnumber 703 A A",
    "answer": " Shri Guru Nanak Dev Ji Marg\n"
}{
    "question": "409)\uf020 Shri Guru Nanak Dev Ji Marg runs from which\nplace to which place",
    "answer": " From Kapurthala\nconnecting Goindwal Sahib and terminating\nnear Tarn Taran in Punjab\n"
}{
    "question": "410)\uf020 Which state has decided to do away with personal \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 89\ninterviews for recruitment of staff and limit the\nprocess only to written examination",
    "answer": " Andhra\nPradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "411)\uf020 The NITI Aayog released it's first-ever India\nInnovation Index to promote competitiveness\namong the states. Which state emerged as the\ntopper",
    "answer": " Karnataka\n"
}{
    "question": "412)\uf020 Government has decided to name India\u2019s longest\ntunnel Chenani- Nashri after Jansangh (now BJP)\nfounder. What is his name",
    "answer": " Dr Shyama Prasad\nMukherjee\n"
}{
    "question": "413)\uf020 Where is the Chennai Nashri Tunnel",
    "answer": " On NH 44,\nin Jammu and Kashmir\n"
}{
    "question": "414)\uf020 India recently handed over a second pair of Mi24V helicopters to which country",
    "answer": " Afghanistan\n"
}{
    "question": "415)\uf020 India ranks at which place among the 128\ncountries surveyed by the Charities Aid\nFoundation",
    "answer": " 82nd\n"
}{
    "question": "416)\uf020 Which country topped the WorldGiving Index",
    "answer": "\nUSA\n"
}{
    "question": "417)\uf020 48th edition of the Indian Handicrafts and Gifts\nFair (IHGF) was held at the India Expo Centre &\nMart in which city",
    "answer": " Greater Noida, UP\n"
}{
    "question": "418)\uf020 Which country announced the establishment of\nworld's first research based Artificial Intelligence\nUniversity",
    "answer": " UAE\n"
}{
    "question": "419)\uf020 Indian Air Force and Royal Air Force of Oman\nheld a joint air warfare exercise named _______",
    "answer": " ExEastern Bridge-V\n"
}{
    "question": "420)\uf020 The Ex-Eastern Bridge-V exercise was hosted by\nwhich country",
    "answer": " Oman\n"
}{
    "question": "421)\uf020 In the memory of which Indian leader World\nStudents\u2019 Day is observed on October 15",
    "answer": " APJ\nAbdul Kalam\n"
}{
    "question": "422)\uf020 Kais Saied has been elected as the new President\nof which country",
    "answer": " Tunisia\n"
}{
    "question": "423)\uf020 Which star footballer was awarded \u2018European\nGolden Shoe\u2019 for being the top goal-scorer in\nleague football across Europe",
    "answer": " Lionel Messi\n"
}{
    "question": "424)\uf020 Lionel Messi hails from which country",
    "answer": "\nArgentina\n"
}{
    "question": "425)\uf020 Indian Railways has announced that it will\nbecome a net-zero carbon emitter by which year",
    "answer": "\n2030\n"
}{
    "question": "426)\uf020 India is the biggest emitter of greenhouse gases\nafter which two other countries",
    "answer": " USA and China\n"
}{
    "question": "427)\uf020 Recently how many heritage landmarks from\nIndia were chosen for the UNESCO Asia-Pacific\nAwards for Cultural Heritage Conservation",
    "answer": " Four\n"
}{
    "question": "428)\uf020 The world observes International Poverty\nEradication Day on which date",
    "answer": " October 17\n"
}{
    "question": "429)\uf020 Among 117 countries surveyed in the Global\nHunger Index (GHI) 2019, India secured which\nrank",
    "answer": " 102\n"
}{
    "question": "430)\uf020 Which airline became the first airline in the world\non October 15 to use a Taxibot on an A320\naircraft with passengers on board",
    "answer": " Air India\n"
}{
    "question": "431)\uf020 RBI has issued guidelines for on-tap authorisation\nfor how many payment systems",
    "answer": " Three\n"
}{
    "question": "432)\uf020 Name the three payment systems for which RBI\nallowed on tap authorization",
    "answer": " Bharat Bill\nPayment Operating Unit (BBPOU), White Label\nATMs (WLAs) and Trade Receivables\nDiscounting System (TReDS)\n"
}{
    "question": "433)\uf020 Which state plans to organised the country\u2019s first\ntraining and performance programme of world\nfamous KHON (\u0916\u094b\u0928) Ramlila",
    "answer": " Uttar Pradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "434)\uf020 The world famous KHON (\u0916\u094b\u0928) Ramlila is\nassociated with which country",
    "answer": " Thailand\n"
}{
    "question": "435)\uf020 What is the single unique feature of the KHON\nRamlila",
    "answer": " It has no dialogues\n"
}{
    "question": "436)\uf020 Which International Day is observed to\ncommemorate the founding of the Food and\nAgriculture Organization (FAO) on October 16,\n1945",
    "answer": " World Food Day (Head.Qrt.-Rome)\n"
}{
    "question": "437)\uf020 Name the organization that launched Food Safety\nMitra",
    "answer": " Food Safety and Standards Authority of\nIndia (FSSAI)\n"
}{
    "question": "438)\uf020 What is the main objective of the recently\nlaunched Food Safety Mitra scheme",
    "answer": " Sensitise\nstreet food vendors and food businesses on\nhygiene and regulatory aspects\n"
}{
    "question": "439)\uf020 Who is the President of Philippines",
    "answer": " Rodrigo\nDuterte\n"
}{
    "question": "440)\uf020 Indian President attended the Enthronement\nCeremony of the Emperor of Japan. What is the\nname of the new Emperor",
    "answer": " HM Naruhito\n"
}{
    "question": "441)\uf020 PriyanshuRajawat claimed the men's singles title\nat the Bahrain International Series of which\nsports",
    "answer": " Badminton\n"
}{
    "question": "442)\uf020 Valtteri Bottas won the Japanese Grand Prix for\nteam Mercedes. He hails from which country",
    "answer": "\nFinland\n"
}{
    "question": "443)\uf020 10th edition of the RashtriyaSanskriti MahotsavNational Cultural Festival was hosted by",
    "answer": "\nMadhya Pradesh\nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 90\n"
}{
    "question": "444)\uf020 Booker Prize-2019, prestigious literary prize was\nawarded jointly to which two authors",
    "answer": " Margaret\nAtwood and Bernardine Evaristo\n"
}{
    "question": "445)\uf020 Margaret Atwood won the Booker Prize-2019 for\nwhich novel",
    "answer": " The Testament\n"
}{
    "question": "446)\uf020 For which novel Bernardine Evaristo won the\nBooker Prize",
    "answer": " Girl, Woman, Other\n"
}{
    "question": "447)\uf020 What is the cash award of the Booker Prize",
    "answer": " GBP\n50,000\n"
}{
    "question": "448)\uf020 Who is the first black women to win the\nprestigious Booker Prize",
    "answer": " Bernardine Evaristo\n"
}{
    "question": "449)\uf020 The nation celebrates\nRashtriyaMahilaKisanDiwas on which date",
    "answer": "\nOctober 15\n"
}{
    "question": "450)\uf020 International Day of Rural Women is celebrated\nacross the world on which day of October",
    "answer": " 15th\n"
}{
    "question": "451)\uf020 Which day is celebrated globally on October 14 to\nraise awareness among regulators, industry and\nconsumers as to the importance of\nstandardization",
    "answer": " World / International\nStandards Day\n"
}{
    "question": "452)\uf020 A commemorative stamp was released in honour\nof the sole Marshal of the Indian Air Force. Give\nhis name",
    "answer": " Marshal of IAF Arjan Singh\n"
}{
    "question": "453)\uf020 India and the US forces held a joint military\nexercise in Seattle, USA. What was its name",
    "answer": "\nVajra Prahar\n"
}{
    "question": "454)\uf020 What is the name of the award constituted by the\nIndian National Congress to honour promoters of\nNational Integration",
    "answer": " Indira Gandhi Award for\nNational Integration\n"
}{
    "question": "455)\uf020 Name the social worker honoured with 31st\nIndira Gandhi Award for National Integration",
    "answer": "\nChandi Prasad Bhatt\n"
}{
    "question": "456)\uf020 Sh. Chandi Prasad Bhatt is known for promoting\n",
    "answer": "Chipko Movement in Uttarakhand to save\ntrees\n"
}{
    "question": "457)\uf020 What is the actual name of the Nobel Prize for\nEconomics",
    "answer": " The SverigesRiksbank Prize in\nEconomic Sciences\n"
}{
    "question": "458)\uf020 Out of six Nobel Prizes announced every year,\nwhich one was not listed in the will of Alfred\nNobel",
    "answer": " Economics\n"
}{
    "question": "459)\uf020 Abhijit Banerjee and his wife Esther Duflo, cowinner of Nobel Prize for economics, are\nassociated with which university",
    "answer": " Massachusetts\nInstitute of Technology, Cambridge, USA\n"
}{
    "question": "460)\uf020 Prime Miniter Narendra Modi has become the\nworld\u2019s most-followed leader on which social\nmedia with more than 30 million followers",
    "answer": "\nInstagram\n"
}{
    "question": "461)\uf020 \u201cProtect Birds be the Solution to Plastic Pollution\u201d\nis the theme of which International Day",
    "answer": " World\nMigratory Bird Day\n"
}{
    "question": "462)\uf020 Which Indian won his maiden BWF (Badminton\nWorld Federation) World Tour title by winning\nthe Dutch Open men's singles at Almere in the\nNetherlands",
    "answer": " Lakshya Sen\n"
}{
    "question": "463)\uf020 Name the 22 year old star US gymnast broke the\nall-time record for most medals by any gymnast\n(male or female) at the world championships by\nsecuring 25 of them",
    "answer": " Simone Biles\n"
}{
    "question": "464)\uf020 R Praggnanandhaa, the 14-year-old Grand Master\nfrom Chennai won the gold in the U-18 Open\ncategory in",
    "answer": "World Youth Chess Championships\nheld in Mumbai\n"
}{
    "question": "465)\uf020 Name the great Indian Nun who was canonised as\nSaint by the Pope Francis",
    "answer": " Mariam Thresia\n"
}{
    "question": "466)\uf020 Name the sole woman boxer who won silver in\nthe women\u2019s World boxing championships",
    "answer": "\nManju Rani\n"
}{
    "question": "467)\uf020 Name the city that hosted the women\u2019s World\nboxing championships",
    "answer": " Ulan Ude, Russia\n"
}{
    "question": "468)\uf020 The king & queen of which European country\nvisited India in October on a five day visit",
    "answer": " The\nNetherlands\n"
}{
    "question": "469)\uf020 What is the popular name of the country The\nNetherlands",
    "answer": " Holland\n"
}{
    "question": "470)\uf020 People of Netherlands are popularly known by\nwhich name",
    "answer": " Dutch\n"
}{
    "question": "471)\uf020 Name the star Indian athlete who created a new\nnational record in the women's 100m race",
    "answer": " Dutee\nChand\n"
}{
    "question": "472)\uf020 Who was declared best female athlete at the 59th\nNational Open Athletics Championships ",
    "answer": "Dutee\nChand\n"
}{
    "question": "473)\uf020 Who was declared best male athlete at the 59th\nNational Open Athletics Championships",
    "answer": "\nTejinderpal Singh Toor\n"
}{
    "question": "474)\uf020 Tejinderpal Singh Toor created new national\nrecord in which event of athletics",
    "answer": " Shot Put\n"
}{
    "question": "475)\uf020 Which athlete created world history by finishing a\nmarathon in less than two hours time",
    "answer": " Eliud\nKipchoge\n"
}{
    "question": "476)\uf020 Eliud Kipchoge hails from which country",
    "answer": " Kenya\n"
}{
    "question": "477)\uf020 Which ministry launched the mobile app \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 91\n\u2018mHariyali\u2019 to promote plantation of trees",
    "answer": "\nMinistry of Housing & Urban Affairs\n"
}{
    "question": "478)\uf020 The second edition of Coordinated Patrol\n(CORPAT) of the navies was conducted between\nnavies of which two countries",
    "answer": " India and\nBangladesh\n"
}{
    "question": "479)\uf020 Who is the present Chief of Indian Navy",
    "answer": "\nAdmiral Karambir Singh\n"
}{
    "question": "480)\uf020 The first ever India International Cooperatives\nTrade Fair was held in which city from Oct 11 to\n13",
    "answer": " New Delhi\n"
}{
    "question": "481)\uf020 Chinese President Xi Jinping arrived in which city\non October 11 for a two-day visit to India",
    "answer": "\nChennai\n"
}{
    "question": "482)\uf020 Chinese President held the informal summit with\nPrime Minister Modi at which heritage\ncity",
    "answer": "Mamallapuram\n"
}{
    "question": "483)\uf020 What is the name of the China's currency",
    "answer": "\nRenminbi\n"
}{
    "question": "484)\uf020 National Voluntary Blood Donation Day is\nobserved on which date",
    "answer": " October 1\n"
}{
    "question": "485)\uf020 Which international day aims to help raise\nawareness of the benefits of eggs and their\nimportance in human nutrition",
    "answer": " The World Egg\nDay\n"
}{
    "question": "486)\uf020 Which day is observed globally to highlight the\nchallenges faced by girls worldwide",
    "answer": "\nInternational Day of Girl Child\n"
}{
    "question": "487)\uf020 International Day of Girl Child is observed on\nwhich date",
    "answer": " October 11\n"
}{
    "question": "488)\uf020 Which UN agency has become the first UN\norganisation to allow transactions in\ncryptocurrency",
    "answer": " UNICEF\n"
}{
    "question": "489)\uf020 Where are the headquarters of UNICEF",
    "answer": " New\nYork\n"
}{
    "question": "490)\uf020 Which Arabian country has recently allowed\nrecruitment of women in its armed forces",
    "answer": " Saudi\nArabia\n"
}{
    "question": "491)\uf020 Which batsman recently recorded his seventh\ndouble hundred, the highest in Indian cricket\nhistory",
    "answer": " ViratKohli\n"
}{
    "question": "492)\uf020 Which Nobel Prize this year had its 100th\ndelivery",
    "answer": " Peace Prize\n"
}{
    "question": "493)\uf020 Abiy Ahmed Ali was selected for the prestigious\nprize for his efforts to achieve peace and\ninternational cooperation. He is Prime Minister of\nwhich country",
    "answer": " Ethiopia\n"
}{
    "question": "494)\uf020 Who decides the winner of Nobel peace prize",
    "answer": " A\nfive member Nobel committee appointed by\nthe Parliament of Norway\n"
}{
    "question": "495)\uf020 The government launched\nSurakshitMatritvaAashwasan, SUMAN with what\nobjective",
    "answer": " To bring down maternal and infant\nmortality rates\n"
}{
    "question": "496)\uf020 Who are the targeted beneficiaries of SUMAN",
    "answer": "\nPregnant women, mothers up to 6 months\nafter delivery, and all sick newborns\n"
}{
    "question": "497)\uf020 A team of astronomers from USA discovered 20\npreviously unknown moons of which planet",
    "answer": "\nSaturn\n"
}{
    "question": "498)\uf020 After this discovery, which planet now has largest\nnumber of moons-82",
    "answer": " Saturn\n"
}{
    "question": "499)\uf020 Saturn planet is predominantly composed of\nwhich two gasses",
    "answer": " Hydrogen and Helium\n"
}{
    "question": "500)\uf020 Which Nobel Prize has been announced this year\nfor 2018 also",
    "answer": " Literature\n"
}{
    "question": "501)\uf020 Who is the winner of the 2018 Nobel Prize in\nliterature",
    "answer": " Olga Tokarczuk, Poland\n"
}{
    "question": "502)\uf020 The 2019 Nobel prize for literature has been won\nby which Austrian author",
    "answer": " Peter Handke\n"
}{
    "question": "503)\uf020 Which authority decides the Nobel Prize in\nliterature",
    "answer": " The Swedish Academy, Stockholm\n"
}{
    "question": "504)\uf020 The Union Cabinet has approved proposal to\ndouble the honorariums for ASHA workers to Rs\n2000/pm. Expand the acronym ASHA",
    "answer": "\nAccredited Social Health Activists\n"
}{
    "question": "505)\uf020 What is the name of the first ever national digital\nplatform and app launched on oral health\ninformation",
    "answer": "EDantseva\n"
}{
    "question": "506)\uf020 Which UN agency supports the celebrations of\ntheWorld Mental Health Day on October 10",
    "answer": "\nWHO- World Health Organisation\n"
}{
    "question": "507)\uf020 Where are the headquarters of WHO",
    "answer": " Geneva,\nSwitzerland\n"
}{
    "question": "508)\uf020 Antonio Costa has been re-elected as the Prime\nMinister of which European country",
    "answer": " Portugal\n"
}{
    "question": "509)\uf020 Who became the first Indian female cricketer to\ncomplete more than 20 years in international\ncricket",
    "answer": "Mithali Raj\n"
}{
    "question": "510)\uf020 RBI has given its final nod to which state to form\nits own bank by merging existing district co-op.\nbanks",
    "answer": " Kerala\n"
}{
    "question": "511)\uf020 India slipped to which place in Global\nCompetitiveness Index 2019, down 10 places from\nits rank in 2018",
    "answer": " 68th\n"
}{
    "question": "512)\uf020 Which country topped the Global \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 92\nCompetitiveness Index 2019",
    "answer": " Singapore\n"
}{
    "question": "513)\uf020 Atal Innovation Mission and NITI Aayog joined\nhands with which UN agency to launch \u201cYouth\nCo",
    "answer": "Lab\u201d programme? United Nations\nDevelopment Programme (UNDP)\n"
}{
    "question": "514)\uf020 What is the objective of the \u201cYouth Co",
    "answer": "Lab\u201d\nprogramme? Toaccelerate social\nentrepreneurship and innovation in young\nIndians\n"
}{
    "question": "515)\uf020 Central Pollution Control Board joined hands with\nwhich municipal corporation to set up the\ncountry\u2019s first e-waste clinic",
    "answer": " Bhopal (Madhya\nPradesh)\n"
}{
    "question": "516)\uf020 Which global IT giant has agreed to promote the\nAyushman Bharat-Pradhan Mantri Jan Arogya\nYojana",
    "answer": " Google\n"
}{
    "question": "517)\uf020 Japan\u2019s __________ won the China Open Tennis\ntournament held in Beijing, China",
    "answer": " Naomi Osaka\n"
}{
    "question": "518)\uf020 Which Indian organization launched a special logo\nto indicate \u201cTrans Fat Free\u201d food items",
    "answer": " The Food\nSafety & Standards Authority of India (FSSAI)\n"
}{
    "question": "519)\uf020 A joint military exercise named KAZIND-2019\nwas held between India and which other country",
    "answer": "\nKazakhstan\n"
}{
    "question": "520)\uf020 The KAZIND-2019 exercise was held in which\ndistrict of Uttarakhand",
    "answer": " Pithoragarh\n"
}{
    "question": "521)\uf020 With which country India conducted the Nomadic\nElephant\u2013XIV military exercise",
    "answer": " Mongolia\n"
}{
    "question": "522)\uf020 The govt launched the National e-Assessment\nScheme for what purpose",
    "answer": " To eliminate human\ninterface between income taxpayers and\nassessing officers\n"
}{
    "question": "523)\uf020 Which popular daily English newspaper of\nwestern India stopped its print edition and\nshifted to digital version",
    "answer": " DNA-Daily News\nAnalysis\n"
}{
    "question": "524)\uf020 Which UN agency hosted the first celebrations of\nthe World Cotton Day on October 09",
    "answer": " World\nTrade Organisation (WTO)(HeadquartersGeneva)\n"
}{
    "question": "525)\uf020 Scientists John Goodenough, Stanley Whittingham\nand Akira Yoshino won the Nobel Prize for\nChemistry for their work in development\nof_________",
    "answer": "Lithium ion battery\n"
}{
    "question": "526)\uf020 Which authority in Sweden decides the winner of\nNobel Prize for Physics and Chemistry",
    "answer": " The Royal\nSwedish Academy of Sciences, Stockholm\n"
}{
    "question": "527)\uf020 How many scientists shared this year's Nobel\nPrize in Physiology/Medicine",
    "answer": " Three\n"
}{
    "question": "528)\uf020 The Nobel Prize in Physiology 2019 has been\nawarded for research in which field",
    "answer": " How cells\nsense and adapt to oxygen availability\n"
}{
    "question": "529)\uf020 The Indian Air Force, IAF celebrated its____\nanniversary on Oct 8",
    "answer": " 87th\n"
}{
    "question": "530)\uf020 What is the motto of the Indian Air Force",
    "answer": "\nNabha\u1e25Spr\t \t \t \t \u0325\u015bha\u1e41D\u012bptam\t (Touch\t the\t sky\t with\t\nglory)\n"
}{
    "question": "531)\uf020 The govt approved a four-fold increase in the\nmonetary assistance provided to the next of kin of\nall battle casualties, from existing Rs 2 lakh to ____\nlakh",
    "answer": " 8\n"
}{
    "question": "532)\uf020 The National Basketball Association (NBA) of USA\nbrought to India the first-ever Floating Basketball\nCourt in which place",
    "answer": " In the Arabian Sea near\nMumbai\n"
}{
    "question": "533)\uf020 _____ of India created three world records at the\nWorld Powerlifting Championship in Berlin,\nGermany",
    "answer": " Surender Singh\n"
}{
    "question": "534)\uf020 India signed an MoU to set up a coastal\nsurveillance radar system in which country",
    "answer": "\nBangladesh\n"
}{
    "question": "535)\uf020 Supreme Court has ruled that road traffic offences\ncan also be prosecuted under ________ , apart from\nthe Motor Vehicles Act",
    "answer": " Indian Penal Code (IPC)\n"
}{
    "question": "536)\uf020 The World Teachers Day is observed on which\nday of October",
    "answer": " 5th\n"
}{
    "question": "537)\uf020 Which ministry launched the Audio Guide facility\n\u201cAudio Odigos\u201d for 12 sites of India",
    "answer": " Tourism\nMinistry\n"
}{
    "question": "538)\uf020 The second Vande Bharat Express train started its\nrun on which route from 5th October",
    "answer": " DelhiKatra route\n"
}{
    "question": "539)\uf020 The first Vande Bharat Express runs between\nDelhi and which other station",
    "answer": " Varanasi\n"
}{
    "question": "540)\uf020 Govt. has appointed Surjit Bhalla, senior\neconomist as Exec. Director of which\ninternational organization",
    "answer": " IMF\n"
}{
    "question": "541)\uf020 Who has been appointed as the MD and CEO of\nthe Punjab National Bank",
    "answer": " S SMallikarjunan Rao\n"
}{
    "question": "542)\uf020 What is the name of the China's recently launched\nintercontinental-range ballistic missile, touted to\nbe the most powerful missile",
    "answer": " Dongfeng-41 (DF41)\n"
}{
    "question": "543)\uf020 Which is the official body that decides the changes\nin the key policy rates of RBI",
    "answer": " Monetary Policy\nCommittee\nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 93\n"
}{
    "question": "544)\uf020 Under Swachh Rail, Swacch Bharat cleanliness\nassessment 2019, carried out by the Ministry of\nRailways, which railway station topped in\ncleanliness",
    "answer": " Jaipur\n"
}{
    "question": "546)\uf020 The phrase \"Sarbat Da Bhala\" has been taken\nfrom which ritual of Sikh religion",
    "answer": " It is the last\nline of the \u2018Ardaas\u2019 (prayer) offered by the\nSikhs\n"
}{
    "question": "547)\uf020 The Sarbat Da Bhala Express train will run from\nwhich place to which place",
    "answer": " New Delhi to Lohian\nKhas via holy city Sultanpur Lodhi\n"
}{
    "question": "548)\uf020 Birth anniversary of Mahatma Gandhi, October\n02, is observed as which International Day across\nthe world",
    "answer": " International Day of Non-Violence\n"
}{
    "question": "549)\uf020 Which day is observed every year with UN\nsupport to highlight the important contribution\nthat older people make to society? October 1",
    "answer": "\nInternational Day of Older Persons\n"
}{
    "question": "550)\uf020 Ms. Sheikh Hasina, ______ of Bangladesh arrived in\nIndia on Oct 3 for a three-day official visit",
    "answer": " Prime\nMinister\n"
}{
    "question": "551)\uf020 Which neibhrouring country of India celebrated\non Oct 01 its 70th anniversary of its founding",
    "answer": "\nChina\n"
}{
    "question": "552)\uf020 Who is popularly known as Founding Father of\nRepublic of China",
    "answer": " Mao Zedong - or Chairman\nMao\n"
}{
    "question": "553)\uf020 President conferred The VayoshreshthaSamman\n2019 on October 03. This award is given to which\ncategory of persons",
    "answer": " Eminent Senior Citizens\n"
}{
    "question": "554)\uf020 SaraswatiSamman 2018 has been conferred upon\nwhich eminent author",
    "answer": " K Siva Reddy\n"
}{
    "question": "555)\uf020 K Siva Reddy is the famous scholar of which\nlanguage",
    "answer": " Telugu\n"
}{
    "question": "556)\uf020 Kallie Puri was honoured in British Parliament as\n\"India\u2019s Most Powerful Women in Media\". Who is\nshe",
    "answer": " Vice-Chairperson of the India Today\nGroup\n"
}{
    "question": "557)\uf020 October 01 is celebrated across the world to\npromote the popularity of which beverage",
    "answer": "\nCoffee\n"
}{
    "question": "558)\uf020 Which day is celebrated annually to raise\nawareness about rabies prevention",
    "answer": " World\nRabies Day, September 28\n"
}{
    "question": "559)\uf020 Name the great scientist who developed the first\nRabies vaccine",
    "answer": " Louis Pasteur\n"
}{
    "question": "560)\uf020 As per the School Education Quality Index\nreleased by the Niti Aayog, which state was\nranked at No. 1",
    "answer": " Kerala\n"
}{
    "question": "561)\uf020 As per the School Education Quality Index\nreleased by the Niti Aayog, which UT was ranked\nat No. 1",
    "answer": " Chandigarh\n"
}{
    "question": "562)\uf020 Which Indian Bank opened its office in Melbourne\non Sep 30, becoming the first Indian bank to have\na branch in the Australian state of Victoria",
    "answer": " State\nBank of India\n"
}{
    "question": "563)\uf020 RBI has announced two contests to promote\ninnovations and ideas in which field",
    "answer": " The\npayment and settlement systems\n"
}{
    "question": "564)\uf020 These contests will be organised through IDRBT,\nHyderabad. Expand IDRBT",
    "answer": " Institute for\nDevelopment and Research in Banking\nTechnology\n"
}{
    "question": "565)\uf020 NASA and the International Astronomical Union\nnamed a minor planet after a great Indian\nclassical singer. Who is he",
    "answer": " Pandit Jasraj\n"
}{
    "question": "566)\uf020 Who has been appointed as the new Chairman of\nthe Chiefs of Staff Committee",
    "answer": " Gen. Bipin Rawat\n"
}{
    "question": "567)\uf020 Which Indian wrestler was ranked number one in\n86 kg category in the latest rankings issued by the\nInternational Wrestling Federation",
    "answer": " Deepak\nPunia\n"
}{
    "question": "568)\uf020 Kaushal Dharmamer is a upcoming star player in\nwhich sports",
    "answer": " Badminton\n"
}{
    "question": "569)\uf020 India defeated which country to win the SAFF\nUnder-18 Championship 2019 in Kathmandu",
    "answer": "\nBangladesh\n"
}{
    "question": "570)\uf020 India was ranked _______ in the IMD World Digital\nCompetitiveness Ranking 2019 for 63 countries",
    "answer": "\n44th\n"
}{
    "question": "571)\uf020 Which country topped the IMD World Digital\nCompetitiveness Ranking 2019",
    "answer": " USA\n"
}